

Claudio Procentese

Costa di San Giorgio, Florence Italy 50125

(+39) 338 1981060

procentese.claudio@gmail.com https://www.procentese.com

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate Python/Java/ PHP developer with over 6 years of professional experience, and am interested in companies that utilize agile development and the latest web or standalone-related technologies.

Languages: Italian (native speaker), English (work proficiency)

SKILLS

WORK Python Java Django Php Linux PERSONAL FAST LEARNER PROBLEM SOLVING TEAM PLAYER SOCIAL

CREATIVITY

CLAUDIO PROCENTESE

Senior Software Engineer

Skills

- Languages: Python, Java/J2EE, PHP, JS, SQL
- Frameworks: Django, Spring, Struts,
 Hibernate, JSF, ibatis, Apache Axis/Camel/Rhino,
 JAAS, JUnit, Jasper Report
- DBMS: Oracle, MS Sql Server, MySql, PostgresSQL, Firebird,
 - MongoDB
- Application server: Nginx, Tomcat, Jboss
- Source management: Git, Svn
- Project management: Hudson, trac, redmine
 - Build automation: Jenkins, Maven
- Tools: PyCharm, Eclipse
- OS: MS Windows, Linux, OS X

EXPERIENCE

(March 2014 - present)

Senior Software Engineer

NiviGroup S.p.A - Florence, IT

Developed several python-based projects based on a proprietary framework for large touchscreen devices. The software helps to control and interact with a natural interface with a large number of controllers and input.

Developed a web-based platform (Django) with the purpose of having a single application to help customers to obtain business information about other companies or individuals.

(May 2012 - Jan 2014)

J2EE Senior Developer

Engineering S.p.A - Florence, IT

Collaborated on a project called "Areas," which is a modular ERP suite for the management of public health structures. The suite is a modular-based software that is usable by a web interface and is invoked by web services (SOA).

The use of this software is very broad and covers the following areas: payment of health services, first aid, operating theatres and personnel management.

(Jun 2011 - May 2012)

J2EE Senior Developer

Monte dei Paschi di Siena S.p.A - Siena, IT

Collaborated on a project called "PaschiFace," a web platform for bank operations. Specifically, I developed the mass production of PDFs for the documents "Delega f24" and "Quietanza F24."

These services were exposed through the use of EJB (3.0). The process was scheduled in batch and ended with the mass production of PDF stored in a documental ERP suite.

(Oct 2009 – Jan 2011)

J2EE junior / PHP Developer

Infocube S.r.I – Naples, IT

Developed several web-based projects, the highlight being for Ansaldo S.p.A. This software was used to keep track of the establishment of new train stations (materials, costs etc.).

(Sep 2008 - Oct 2009)

J2DK junior developer / PHP

Engineering S.a.s - Naples, IT

Collaborated on a CRM software utilized by a call center that was developed using Java/Swing integrating Asterisk PBX VoIP.

(May 2008 - Sep 2008)

J2DK developer

Tributaria Italia S.p.A - Naples, IT

Developed a client/server Java desktop application used by public administration for the calculation of wasted taxes.

(Jan 2005 - Oct 2007)

PHP Developer

Muir & Associates Inc – Jacksonville, Florida US

Developed a platform for a credit recovery service that was used by customers to sign in to personal services and procure payments online, and by the owners to monitor clients and credit services.

(Mar 2005 - Sep 2006)

PHP Developer

Servizi Aziendali S.r.I - Naples, IT

Designed a web platform for the release of company proprietary software. This restricted-access platform had multiple roles, such as email update notifications sent to customers and prompts to download software updates.

EDUCATION

(2002 -)

Bachelor Of Science

Università federico II, Naples, IT - Computer Science Courses in programming languages, math, statistic, parallel computing etc.

(1997 - 2002)

Diploma

Scientific High School